# Priyanka Saggu

Ward #14, Fatehabad Haryana, India 125050 (+91) 8168904724 priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com

June 08, 2020

# **Hiring Manager**

Red Hat Brno, Czech Republic

With reference to the opening you've advertised at the company's job portal, for the *Automation Engineer - Virtualization* position (Job Id 77347), I am attaching my resume for your review.

Packing an year long of experience working as a DevOps Engineer, I also am proficient in the following skills by building several practical projects and creating highly scalable, production-ready pipelines.

- Experience working with highly distributed infrastructure on hybrid cloud platforms (GCP, AWS, On-Prem).
- Experience building solutions for On-Premise multi-cluster application deployments setup using Rancher, further
  expanding to Cluster monitoring, health-checks, alerts, managing updates/upgrades and finally disaster
  recovery with Velero.
- Deep familiarity with embedded DevOps tools and best practices, like:
  - → Docker, Docker-swarm & Kubernetes for container orchestration.
  - → Ansible & Jinja templates for writing Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to automate setting up of tightly-secured and ssh hardened systems/servers.
  - → Helm/Helm-charts for packaging microservice architecture (or multi-cluster) applications.
  - → Prometheus, Grafana & Loki for metrics monitoring, logging & configuring alerts.
  - → CircleCl and Github Actions for writing Cl/CD pipelines.
  - → Replicated/KOTS for end-to-end product release & license management.

I believe I am a good fit for the position and am ready to meet the challenges of the position, bringing value to your organization.

My previous work experience at a DataOps organisation, has resulted in a high level of expertise in writing & maintaining infrastructure for industrial use. In one instance, I've worked on optimizing the cost of running an entire data cataloging & discovery stack by 40%, bringing in a lite version of the product.

I am available for an interview at your convenience and would welcome the opportunity to discuss my experience and qualifications further as they relate to your needs.

My email address is <u>priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com</u> and my phone number is +91 8168904724. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Sincerely,

Priyanka Saggu

# Priyanka Saggu

Resourceful DevOps enthusiast, having experience working with highly distributed infrastructure on hybrid cloud platforms. Having a years long experience as a DevOps Engineer, I've been writing fully automated product releases, with minimal interference on the client enterprise end. As a contributor at <a href="Linux Users Group of Durgapur">Linux Users Group of Durgapur</a>, I have set up and managed multiple Linux-based servers. Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to automate setting up of tightly-secured and SSH-hardened systems/ servers using Ansible & Jinja templates. Also, carrying an experience with On-Prem deployment environments setup using Rancher. And I'm an <a href="Outreachy'19 alumna at GNOME Foundation">Outreachy'19 alumna at GNOME Foundation</a> too.

**EXPERIENCE** 

## AtlanHQ

— DevOps Engineer

(FEB 2020 - PRESENT)

Working at a DataOps organisation, has resulted in a high level of expertise in writing & maintaining infrastructure for industrial use. In one instance, I've worked on optimizing the cost of running an entire data cataloging & discovery stack by 40%, bringing in a lite version of the product.

## **GNOME Foundation**

— Outreachy'19 Intern

(DEC 2019 - MAR 2020)

Enhanced <u>GNOME Translation Editor (gtranslator)</u> UI by revamping existing widgets in accordance with Gnome Human Interface Guidelines (HIG). Besides, entirely redesigning the old search and replace bar dialog to a new sliding overlay style custom widget, using libdazzle library.

Contributions: https://gitlab.gnome.org/users/priyankasaggu119/activity

# Linux Users Group of Durgapur (DGPLUG)

(JUN 2018 - PRESENT)

Set up and managed multiple Linux distribution servers.

- Wrote Ansible scripts to automatically update system components and setup production environments.
- Set up a WriteFreely multi-user instance behind reverse-proxy.
- Set up multiple Docker containers, orchestrated using Docker Swarm, for carrying out test deployments.
- Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to setup SSH-hardened servers.
- Contributed to lymworkbook a Vagrant lab environment in setting up a few basic level sys-admins problems.
- Setup OpenVPN service, creating both OpenVPN server and Certificate Authority (CA) server on different machines.

# **Debian Project**

(AUG 2019 - OCT 2019)

- Packaged 4 django/flask dependency python modules under Debian-Python-Modules-Team (DPMT).
- Packaged and updated 5+ ruby-gems for Debian-Diaspora project under Debian-Ruby-Team (DRT).
- Contributed to the Debian-gitlab project under Debian-javascript-team (DJT). Improved old node modules, packaged new ones and was constantly involved in testing of Debian-gitlab for then-stable version release.

Contributions: https://salsa.debian.org/users/priyankasaggu119-guest/activity

#### **WRITINGS**

- Automating private dataproc cluster deployment having Presto Installation (on GCP)!
- Custom GCP type provider for automating VPC Network Peering Creation!
- Parse Server On-Premise Deployment
- A guide to a "safer" SSH!
- Consul Key-Value Store!
- Let's get started with iptables!
- Automating WordPress Installation through Ansible!
- Setting up WriteFreely multi-user instance in production

Email: priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com

Website: <a href="https://priyankasaggu11929.github.io/">https://priyankasaggu11929.github.io/</a>

**Gitlab-gnome:** https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119 **Gitlab-salsa:** https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119

Github: https://github.com/Priyankasaggu11929/

## **SKILLS/ KEYWORDS**

Linux: Debian family (Ubuntu, Debian Buster), Red Hat

family (CentOS)

Scripting: Bash and utils, Python

Backend: Python (Django)

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript (JQuery, PhaserJS)

**GUI Toolkit:** GTK+ 3 in pure C **Databases:** MySQL, SQLite

Web Application servers/proxies: Nginx, Apache2

Version control systems: Git

Markup & Documentation: LaTeX, Pandoc, Markdown

**DevOps:** Kubernetes, Rancher, Ansible, Docker, Docker Swarm, Helm/Helm Charts, Prometheus & Grafana, Loki, Velero, Weave Cloud, Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), RabbitMQ, Replicated/KOTS, CircleCI, Github Actions

**Misc:** Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), OpenCV, Java-J2SE

## **EDUCATION**

Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal (Sonipat), Haryana

B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

AUGUST 2015 - MAY 2019

**Government Model Senior Secondary School,** Sector 35-D, Chandigarh (U.T.)

— AISSCE (12th - PCM)

APRIL 2015 - APRIL 2019

**S.B.P. D.A.V Centenary Public School,** Fatehabad, Haryana

— AISSE (10th)

APRIL 2012 - APRIL 2013

#### **CONFERENCES/ EVENTS**

- **2020** Delivered the talk "Introduction to Github Actions" at <a href="PyLadies">PyLadies</a>, <a href="Delivered">Delhi Meetup</a>.
- **2019** Volunteer at PyCon, India
- **2019** DebUtsav, Delhi
- 2017 Volunteer at International Conference on Textile Advances-TAI India

## **REFERENCES**

 Chandan Kumar, OpenStack/RDO developer, Red Hat, chkumar AT redhat DOT com